Sara Al Mughairy

Product Designer

A strategic designer with roots in research and a talent for translating data into user-centered products.

Contact

Address_Seattle, WA 98122 Mobile_951 541 3568 Email_ sawra@uw.edu

Portfolio

Web_sawra.tech
Git_github.com/sawraw
Lin_linkedin.com/in/sawra

Research + Design

Skills_Ideation / Wireframing / Storyboarding / Stakeholder Mapping / Journey Mapping/ Personas / Data Visualization / Paper Prototyping / Card Sorting / Competitive Analysis / User interviews / Focus Groups / Field Studies / Diary Studies

Tools_ Illustrator / InDesign / ExperienceDesign / Sketch / Invision / Principle / Tableau

Engineering

Proficient_JavaScript / HTML / CSS3 / React / Redux / Node / Express / Sequelize / Git / SQL / Bootstrap

Familiarity_D3 / JQuery /
SASS / A-Frame.js / Electron
/ Webpack / Python / Auth0 /
Jasmine / Arduino

Selected Projects

Ramble_Ideation and UX of an app that helps women be and feel safer walking alone, while collecting actionable data for city planners (sponsored by REI).

VideoTurbine_Ideation, Market Research, UX, and Web Development of a web service that makes video production more accessible to businesses (my startup).

DataLab_Design & development of a BI desktop app that empowers organizations to create and share real-time data visualizations sourced from the data in their local databases.

Experience

Sep 2015 - Aug 2016

HCI Events Coordinator (Grad Asst) @ University of Washington HCI + Design Dep't Organized HCI programs, such as the Design-Use-Build weekly seminar for > 100 attendees.

Mar 2015 - Jul 2015

UX Designer (Research Data Scientist) @ **UC Berkeley-Haas Neuroeconomics Lab** Transformed laborious economic research paradigms into engaging iPhone games.

Sep 2013 - Jul 2015

Research Manager (Lab Asst II) @ UC Berkeley Language and Cognitive Development Lab Recruited, trained, & mentored over 30 RAs, Managed up to 8 studies at a time, Launched immersive Summer Internship program that attracted precocious students from all over the country, Conducted international research with collaborators from Stanford, Yale, and UCSD, Designed lab website, Co-wrote IRB's, grants, and publications.

Jun 2013 - Aug 2013

Research Assistant (Immersive Internship) @ **Harvard Lab for Developmental Studies** Iteratively modified experimental design to study participants as young as 18-months-old

2010 - 2013, Undergraduate Research and Teaching Experience

Teaching Assistant @ Northeastern University Intro to Cognitive Science Course

Research Assistant @ EMD Serono Protein and Cell Sciences Lab

Research Assistant @ Northeastern University Neuropharmacology Lab

Health Educator @ Peer Health Exchange Boston Public High Schools

Education

Jan 2017 - May 2017

Software Engineering @ **Fullstack Academy** (top ranked coding bootcamp) 50 States of Code scholarship recipient, won awards in two internal hackathons

Sep 2015 - Aug 2016

Master of Human-Computer Interaction + Design @ University of Washington (3.98 GPA) Vice Chair of UW GPSS Diversity Committee

Sep 2010 - Jan 2013

BS. Behavioral Neuroscience @ Northeastern University (3.98 GPA)
Academic scholarship recipient, Sears B. Conduit Academic Achievement Award